♪♪
Mr. Larson.
- Thank you.
As soon as the judge heard that,
he called a recess, and
took us into his chambers,
and he lit into the D.A.
like there was no tomorrow.
I mean,
all the poor guy could
do was move to dismiss.
Why do I even bother?
With what?
Going to law school.
When I can learn everything
I need to know from you.
Well, there's no substitute
for experience, Andrea.
Yeah, you've
taught me that, too.
Oh, did you have a
chance to talk to Larry Klein
about my clerking with
his firm this summer?
No, I didn't.
But you will?
Of course.
Next time I see him.
Promise.
So when is the next
time I'm going to see you?
Is tomorrow soon enough?
How about tonight?
I got to work late.
Oh.
Tell you what, why don't we meet
at the apartment
tomorrow and have lunch?
Better yet, we could
meet at the apartment
and not have lunch.
Um, got to get back.
Tomorrow, 12:30?
Can't wait.
Oh, uh, M-Mr. Larson.
Here are your messages.
And Mr. Jordan is waiting.
Ed Jordan?
What's he doing here?
He had a 2:00 appointment.
Why in the hell
didn't you tell me?!
I told you this morning.
Your job isn't just to tell me,
it's to make sure that I know.
Ed Jordan is important.
You've embarrassed me, Phyllis.
Mr. Larson...
And the next time
that it happens, that's it.
And I mean it.
Ed, I'm terribly sorry.
My girl neglected to remind
me that you were coming in.
Please, have a seat.
Get a pen and write this down.
Find two clean cups,
fill them with coffee
and bring them to us.
Did you get that, dear?
Yes, sir.
Phyllis, for what it's worth,
I heard you tell
him about that 2:00.
You'd think, after all these
years, that I'd get used to it.
He seems to get worse and worse.
I know.
Well, you know he's
not gonna fire you.
Oh, no.
He enjoys humiliating
me too much.
I can't quit because, at my
age, who would hire me?
Trapped like a rat in a cage.
Oh, what can you do?
I don't know.
It's a terrible thing to say,
but sometimes I
wish he were dead.
Oh, Frank.
Eh, it must be the vitamins.
Listen, I'll call you
tomorrow, 2:00, 2:30, and we
can get together later, okay?
Ride down with me?
What do you got in mind?
Well, we are 40 floors up.
Andrea.
What are you doing here?
You were supposed to
be working late, remember?
I brought you dinner.
Who was that?
Her name's Carol.
How long has this been going on?
It's none of your business.
It's over with us, Andrea.
The hell it is.
You're a grown-up, Andrea.
You knew you weren't the first.
Surely you didn't
think you'd be the last.
Nobody dumps me, Frank.
Nobody!
Look, I enjoyed
you, you enjoyed me.
Now we both need a change.
What about that job you
were setting up for me?
I can hardly ask Larry Klein
to hire a girl I
used to sleep with.
Used to sleep with?!
Yes!
Past tense!
Go away.
I'm busy.
Andrea?
Is that you?
Yeah, Mom, it's me.
I ordered some pizza.
There's plenty left.
No, thanks.
I thought you said you
wouldn't be back till after 10:00.
I have to tell you something.
What is it?
Mom, I had an affair
with Frank Larson.
My Frank Larson?
Yes.
How could you?!
I know you hate him, Mom.
It's just that he
was so nice to me.
He... he called me
and he sent me flowers.
He told me he loved me.
He seduced you.
Oh, God.
My poor baby.
Why didn't you tell me?
I think I killed him.
What?
I killed him.
What?!
What ha... what happened?!
I went to his office tonight,
only he was there
with another woman.
And after she left,
I confronted him.
He laughed at me, Mom.
He said that...
I wasn't his first
and I wouldn't be his last.
I was just so hurt,
and I was so angry, I didn't
know what I was doing!
I picked up a-a bookend
and hit him over the head.
But I...
Did, uh, d-did anyone see you?
No. No.
How did you get
into the building?
How'd you get in?
I took your card.
G-G-Give it to me.
How, uh... What did you do?
W-With the bookend.
I-I threw it in a Dumpster
somewhere downtown.
I-I didn't even realize
it was still in my hand
until I was out at my car.
If anyone asks you,
you tell them that
you were here all night.
You were studying.
You hear me?
Yeah.
What are you gonna do?
I'm going to make
sure that bastard's death
doesn't ruin your life.
You take a shower and go to bed.
♪♪
No, the, uh, janitor's
absolutely right.
I was in the office last night.
I just didn't kill Mr. Larson.
What were you doing
there in the first place?
Mr. Larson and I had
kind of a blowup yesterday.
He embarrassed me in
front of the whole office.
More or less
threatened to fire me.
I went to the office last night
to try and smooth things over.
I knew he was working late.
When I got there,
his door was closed.
He was talking to somebody.
So I went out to my car.
I-I read the paper.
About 45 minutes later, I
went back to the office and...
whoever he was
talking to was gone.
And he was dead.
I just turned around and I ran.
I know I should've
called the police,
but it was such a shock.
Besides, I'd be lying if I
said that it didn't occur to me
that I might be blamed.
This person he was talking
to... Have any idea who it was?
No.
- Man or woman?
- Man.
If you heard his voice again,
you think you'd recognize it?
I might.
No.
His voice was too muffled.
Oh.
Muffled.
You worked for
him for a long time?
22 years.
Mm.
You say he
threatened to fire you?
Lately, he's been threatening
to find someone younger.
Will you take my case?
Well...
Mr. Matlock, I did
not kill Frank Larson.
That is the absolute
God's honest truth.
Well, let's see if we
can get you out of here.
Morning, morning.
Bobby.
Morning, Ben.
So you took her case, huh?
Yeah, she's a nice lady.
Have you found
the murder weapon?
Uh, no.
But we know he was
struck over the head once
with a heavy, flat-edged object.
So we're assuming it's the
bookend that matches this.
Killer must have taken
it with her when she fled.
- With him.
- Hmm?
With him. It was a man.
How do you know that?
Sure.
Uh, my client heard Frank Larson
arguing with, uh,
somebody 45 minutes before,
before she, uh.
She found the body.
And, uh, um, said it was a man.
Right.
I don't suppose
you've run into anybody
could give us an
idea who it was?
No.
But if you're gonna
look, you better do it fast.
Frank Larson's widow wants
all of his personal effects
cleared out of here
as soon as possible.
Oh, in a hurry, huh?
- Easy.
- Okay.
Mrs. Larson.
Uh... uh, hi.
- Watch it.
- Hi. I'm Ben Matlock.
I represent Phyllis Todd.
Hello. The matching
end tables go, too.
Everything in the study goes.
Yes, ma'am.
Are you moving?
No. No.
I'm just getting
rid of a few things
- I have no use for anymore.
- Oh.
Whoa.
What a nice desk!
It was my husband's.
Oh, you're getting rid of
all your husband's things?
Well, he's dead, isn't he?
Yeah.
Yeah, he... he's been that way
for close to a whole day now.
Yes.
Uh, I guess he has.
You, uh, you didn't get along?
Oh, no, no.
We got along just fine.
He had his affairs, I had mine.
Oh.
Were they b-business, uh,
or-or-or pleasure af-affairs?
Both.
Oh.
Was he seeing, um,
somebody recently?
He was always seeing
somebody recently.
Would you have any
idea who they were?
I couldn't have cared less.
Did you know your husband
was gonna be
working late last night?
Oh, sure.
Did you do anything special?
Yes, I went to the
East Side Athletic Club,
played tennis with
some friends, had dinner.
And you were there
till... Well, let's see.
We got there about 6:00.
Uh, we were there
till about 10:00.
Sorry, ma'am.
No problem.
Those are Frank's golf trophies.
Most, if not all of them,
completely undeserved.
Oh.
He cheated at that, too.
Hey, Michelle.
- Hey.
- Is Ben here?
He just left to go see Phyllis.
Check out the athletic club?
Yeah. Laura Larson was
there from 6:00 to 10:00
just like she said.
Witnesses all over the place.
Hmm. Well, I didn't get very far
with Phyllis's coworkers either.
Everybody loves her, hated him,
and have no idea
who he could've been
talking to in his
office last night.
This guy Larson, he kills me.
I can understand a guy wanting
to have a fling now and then.
But, I mean, Larson
wanted to have them all.
Well, it's a two-way street.
He did get a little
help, you know.
From who?
From women.
Oh, he wouldn't have
been nearly so successful
in all his so-called conquests
if he didn't get a
signal from women.
Uh, what kind of signal?
The three A's.
I'm approachable, I'm
agreeable, I'm available.
A woman can have just
about any man she wants
when she sends
out those signals.
Oh...
Any man?
Yeah, it happens.
Even, say, someone like Ben?
Oh, Conrad.
Exactly.
You make goo-goo eyes at him,
you wiggle your
little antenna at him,
and he won't even notice it.
He'll probably start
shining his shoes
or scratch his back
up against the wall.
Because he won't fall for it.
I guarantee you
he won't fall for it.
I think you're wrong, Conrad.
Then do it.
What?
You do it.
Give Ben the signal.
I got 50 bucks that
says it won't work.
Unless of course you
don't think you can do it.
Yeah.
Oh, I'm tempted.
Ooh, then try it.
You got the signals,
but I know Ben Matlock.
- You're on.
- Great!
- 50 bucks.
- Hi.
- Oh.
I hope you don't
mind my stopping by.
I-I want to ask you something.
Of course not. Come on in.
You're sure I'm
not interrupting?
No, not at all.
Uh, Andrea.
Come and meet my attorney.
This is Ben Matlock.
Oh.
How do you do?
Oh... I hear you're
in law school.
Yes, I am.
My daughter went to law school
and practices in Philadelphia.
If I sound like a proud
father, it's because I am.
That's wonderful, Mr. Matlock.
I hope my mother can
say the same someday.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Would you like some lemonade?
Oh, no, thank you.
You wanted to ask me something.
Uh, yeah, yeah.
I had an opportunity
to-to speak with, uh,
Frank Larson's widow.
And apparently, he-he wasn't
what-what you'd
call... faithful.
That does not surprise me.
I was hoping maybe
you could help me
figure out what lady
or ladies he was seeing.
You mean, you think he
might have been murdered
by a jealous husband?
Oh, could be, could be.
A lot of women phoned.
I never knew who they were.
You might look
at the phone logs.
They're in my
desk at the office.
Oh, okay. I'll do that.
Thank you, thank you.
That's it?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's it.
E-Except I'm glad to
finally meet you, Andrea.
Same here, Mr. Matlock.
And thank you for
taking my mother's case.
Oh, it's a pleasure.
And as-as one
legal mind to another,
uh, is there anything
you remember
about the night of the murder
that might help your mother?
Oh.
I wish I did.
Um... I came home around 6:30.
She left to talk to
Mr. Larson at around 7:30.
I ordered a pizza,
studied and went to bed.
- Ah.
- That's it.
Okay. Thank you. Okay.
Well, I'll-I'll, uh, be
talking with you. Bye.
Hi, Michelle.
Well?
Well, I just went through
two years worth of phone logs.
Mm-hmm? Find anything?
Yeah.
A pattern.
I'm assuming that the women
who called Frank
Larson most frequently
were the women
he had affairs with,
Shelly, Trish, Linda,
Melanie and Denise.
How did he have
time to practice law?
Well, maybe because
he saw one at a time.
Now, now, see,
Shelly called him every
day for about four months.
And then her calls
stopped and Trish's began.
She called him for
about four months,
and then Linda's calls began.
Anything wrong?
No.
Go ahead.
Well, the really
interesting thing is,
about four months ago,
Denise's calls stopped,
but nobody else's began.
Maybe he needed a rest.
Well, Mrs. Larson
said she thought
that he was cheating on her
right up till the night he died.
Well, then he was.
Wives always know.
Maybe his last affair
never called the office.
- Huh.
- But why?
I don't know.
Something has gotten in here.
Oh, I know.
The exterminator
was here yesterday.
But the smell's
usually gone by now.
Hmm.
So, this was Larson's love nest.
He didn't rent it for
the view, did he?
I'll check the bedroom.
Okay.
Mm-hmm.
Nothing.
Nothing?
He didn't have many
home-cooked meals, either.
Ever heard of
D'Amato's restaurant?
- No.
- Huh.
Yeah. I knew Frank Larson.
I mean, I knew who he was.
He came in here all the time.
In fact, he came in
here the day he died.
Was he with anybody?
Some blonde.
He's been bringing her
in for a couple of months.
We are talking
young and gorgeous.
Did you get a name on her?
No. But I did overhear her
saying something
once that blew me away.
Yeah? What was that?
She was talking about
taking some criminal law class.
I couldn't believe it.
This beautiful chick
was going to law school.
I had a huge dinner last
night. It was a turkey burger.
Oh, hi. Glad you could make it.
Want some coffee?
Oh, no thanks.
I've got to get back
to my study group.
Oh.
Is something wrong
with my mother?
Oh, no. No. I just wanted
to give you something.
Black's Law Dictionary?
- You're giving this to me?
- Yeah.
It was my daughter's and
she doesn't need it anymore,
and I thought maybe
you could use it.
Uh, yes, I can.
- Thank you.
- Yeah, yeah.
Well, I'd better get back.
Okay.
My best to your mother.
Tell me, Mr. Matlock,
how's her case going?
Um, it's fine.
It's coming along.
Good.
- Yeah.
- Thanks again for the book.
- Okay.
- Buh-bye.
Bye.
- Well?
- That's her.
That's the blonde that
Frank Lawson was with.
Something else, isn't she?
Yeah, she sure is.
Miss Hawkins?
Miss Hawkins!
Mm-hmm?
- Will you get that?
- Uh-huh.
Uh-huh?
Oh, Miss Thomas, I
hardly recognize you.
Shh, shh, shh.
What have you done to yourself?
Oh, nothing, really.
It's probably my new hairdo.
Well, you certainly look nice.
Hi, Ben.
Hi, Michelle.
Here's a little bit of news
that will curl your eyebrows.
Andrea was having an
affair with her mother's boss.
- No.
- Yeah.
Now, that puts a whole new
wrinkle on things, doesn't it?
Yeah.
I guess that's why the
phone calls stopped.
Yeah. She couldn't
call him at the office.
Her mother would find out.
Might explain
something else, too.
What's that?
Why he's dead.
Her four months were up.
What?
Do that again.
Do what again?
That-That little walk.
You mean up and down here?
Up and down.
You like-like this? Yeah.
That's it. That's it.
- That's it. That's it.
- What?
- That's it.
That's it. Ernie Ford...
Ernie Ford said a line
to Lucille Ball on
a show one time.
She was walking this
little wiggly walk like that.
He said, "Ma'am, you got
a itch in your get-along."
Whoo!
You got an itch
in your get-along.
Excuse me, Mr. Matlock.
Would you like me
to fix you some lunch?
Sure. Want some lunch?
Uh, why don't we go out?
You want to go out? Okay.
Thank you, Miss Hawkins, anyway.
Where you want to go?
Well, the weather is so nice.
Why don't we eat alfresco?
Al who?
- Outdoors.
- Oh.
It's so pleasant
and we can talk.
Okay.
I know just the place.
Hey, taxi! Taxi!
What a wonderful idea.
The sidewalk cafe.
What's it called?
Alfresco.
Alfresco. A hot dog in the park.
I must remember that.
Well, poor Frank Larson.
Doesn't know what
he's missing, does he?
You know, if he was
a creature of his habit,
he must have been in the process
of changing partners
when he was murdered.
Yeah.
He dumped Andrea.
Think maybe she's
a very poor loser?
Maybe.
And... maybe her
mother's covering for her.
You think maybe Phyllis
found out what was going on?
Was outraged and
maybe did it herself?
Well, that, too. That, too.
There's only one
way to find out.
What's everybody
looking at us for?
I have no idea.
Want another?
No, thanks.
Garçon.
- Oh.
- Hi.
You got a minute to talk?
I've got all the
time in the world.
Is Andrea at home?
Uh, no. She's in class.
Oh, she was thrilled with
that book you gave her,
by the way.
Books are such
treasures for her.
Good.
She's always been
such a good student.
I-I imagine she has
lots of boyfriends.
Not really.
Getting an education
is the most important
thing in her life right now.
You must know the
most important thing
is for the client to
be completely honest
with her lawyer.
You don't think
I'm being honest?
I don't think you're
telling me everything.
Of course I am.
Well, what about Andrea's
affair with Frank Larson?
That's none of your business.
None of my business?
And it's got nothing
to do with my case.
The D.A. won't
look at it that way.
The D.A. doesn't know.
Phyllis, if I found
out about it,
it's likely she'll
find out about it.
And-And I have
to defuse this thing
before she takes it
into the courtroom
and uses it to blow
us out of the water.
No. No.
I absolutely forbid you
to bring this up in court.
It's an embarrassment.
It would ruin my
daughter's career
before it's even begun.
Your word, Mr. Matlock,
or I get a new lawyer.
Miss Richards, you
work for the law firm
of McPherson, Steele,
Larson and Marcus,
is that correct?
Yes, it is. I've been
there almost six years.
And on the day Frank
Larson was murdered,
did you witness an argument
between him and the defendant,
Phyllis Todd?
Well, yes, but it was more
of a misunderstanding, really.
And... and it wasn't a big deal,
because it
happened all the time.
I see.
Did they argue frequently?
Well, Mr. Larson was a
very difficult man to work for.
Just answer the
question, please.
Yes, they did.
Would you say that
this particular argument
upset the defendant?
Phyllis is very sensitive.
They always upset her.
And when you
tried to console her,
what did she say to you?
Well, I can't remember
her exact words.
Your own words
will be just fine.
Uh, she didn't mean it.
What did she say?
She said, "I know it's
a terrible thing to think,
but sometimes I
wish he were dead."
Thank you, Miss Richards.
Ah!
Oh, hi!
Mom told me you know
about the affair
I had with Frank.
I'm so ashamed, Mr. Matlock,
and so grateful that you're
not gonna make it public.
Well, your mother told me
she'd fire me if I did.
She needs you
desperately, Mr. Matlock.
And I'm gonna stand
by her as are you.
You're pretty close to
your mother, aren't you?
I love her very much.
She told me that your father
ran off when you
were a little girl.
Must have been very difficult
for your mother and you.
We had each other.
You've made her very proud.
You're almost a lawyer,
and you did it all yourself.
You don't owe anybody
anything except her.
Ben... Oh, excuse me, but
I just overheard something
I think you ought to know about.
Excuse me.
Sure.
I just heard Julie tell
Lieutenant Brooks to step up
his search for the
murder weapon.
Says if and when
the police find it,
she can wrap this
case up in a day.
She has a new lead.
Sounds like it.
You better be careful.
You might break a
fingernail or something.
Could you help me?
I'm looking for something
that got thrown out
in here by mistake.
I'll pay you.
What's it look like?
It's a, it's a marble bookend.
It's about this big.
It's got a flat bottom
and an angular top.
It's, it's really heavy.
Where are you going?!
I just gave you $20!
It'll cost you $50.
$50 more?
It's a bargain.
In another ten seconds
it'll cost you $60 more.
All right.
Nice doing business
with you, sweetie.
Eh.
If Ben could see you like
this, he'd go for you in a minute.
Just drive.
How'd it go?
She bought it... literally.
Went for the whole thing?
I got 70 bucks out of her.
I don't think she believed
for a second that it was a fake.
Looks like we found
the killer, Conrad.
Looks like.
You ready?
I think so.
I'm a little nervous.
Well, I won't be asking you
any questions about you
and, you know, Frank Larson.
Look at it this way...
As a student of law, it
might be good for you
to see how it feels
up on the stand, right?
- Right.
You know, your
mother still thinks
you're the sweet young girl
that she devoted her life to
after your father left.
You make it sound
like you don't.
Well, it's hard to imagine
a sweet young girl
falling for somebody
like Frank Larson.
Could be you wanted
something else.
Like what?
Maybe a job.
You're wrong about
me, Mr. Matlock.
I hope so.
We have a big problem, Andrea.
I don't think your mother
has much of a chance in there.
You think they'll
find Mom guilty?
I've done my best,
but I have to be honest.
It doesn't look good.
But she's innocent, and
she said you were the best.
She said that you
would get her off!
Well, there seems to be
a big difference these days
between the way your
mother sees things
and the way they really are.
You, you are the, uh, uh,
daughter of the defendant.
Is that correct?
Yes, I am.
And you live together
in the same house?
Yes.
Did your mother ever talk to you
about her employer Frank Larson?
Yes.
Di-Did you get the impression
that she enjoyed
working for him?
He paid her well,
but I don't think
she actually enjoyed
working for him, no.
Why not?
He was very
unpleasant and unfair.
He used to blame her for
things that were his fault
and he used to belittle her
in front of everybody
at the office.
How long was he unfair to her?
For as long as I can remember.
So arguments with her
were a fairly common
everyday occurrence?
Yes.
When you came home
the night of the murder,
did your mother appear
to be angry or distraught?
No.
Did she tell you of the
most recent argument
he had had with her?
All she said was that
she needed to talk to him,
which was why she
went back that night.
She knew he'd be working late.
Uh-huh. And she left
the house at what time?
Oh, 7:15, 7:30,
something like that.
And what, what, what did
you do while she was gone?
I studied, and
then I went to bed.
Well, uh, did, uh...
You-you didn't have,
you didn't have dinner?
I think I ate on
campus that night.
Oh, I remember now.
I, um, I ordered a pizza.
Oh.
What time did the,
uh, did the pizza arrive?
Um, just before 8:00, I guess.
Uh-huh, was your
mother home by then?
No, she didn't get home
until after I'd gone to bed
sometime around 9:00 or so.
So, you, you accepted
delivery of the pizza.
Yes.
Okay. Mr. Matthews.
Do you recognize this man?
No.
Your Honor, I have to
confer with my attorney.
You're out of order.
Please sit down.
I must talk to you.
I agree with you, Your
Honor. She's out of order.
You can't do this.
You're out of order!
You can't!
Now sit down or I'll
have you removed.
You don't recognize this man?
No.
Well, the fact is he doesn't
recognize you either.
He's the man who
delivered the pizza
to your house that night,
and he says the door was opened
not by you, but by
her, your mother.
Objection! Mr. Matlock
can't testify for the witness!
He saw her because
she was at home.
And your mother didn't use
that card to enter the building
that night, did she?
Stop it!
Madam!
You did, didn't you?!
I'm changing my plea!
I'm guilty!
Bailiff, restrain this woman.
Andrea, who killed Frank Larson?
I did!
I killed him!
You must stop him, Judge!
Bailiff, remove the defendant!
No!
Don't.
Who killed Frank Larson?
I killed him.
No.
I was having an affair with him.
Andrea, please.
He broke it off.
I was so stunned and so furious.
I didn't know what I was doing.
I killed him.
Mom went back that
night to cover up for me.
That's why the
janitor saw her there.
I can't let you do it, Mom.
I can't.
Baby.
Oh, baby.
Uh-uh.
Mm-hmm.
What is that?
You remember the deal:
a response from Ben
by the last day of the trial.
I assume there's
been no response,
so... subsequently,
$50.00, please.
You said the last day.
- The day is not over yet.
- Oh, come on. Come on.
If he hasn't cracked by
now, what makes you think
that at the eleventh
hour he's going to come
charging up here and g...?
Oh, Michelle, I'm
glad I caught you.
Uh, I know this is short
notice, but are you busy tonight?
Why, no, Ben, I'm not.
- Uh, you like opera?
- Oh, I love opera.
A friend of mine has tickets,
and he can't use them,
and you are the first
person I thought of.
Oh, Ben, it's so sweet
of you to think of me.
Thank you.
As it happens, I
can't go, either.
They're yours.
Take anybody you like.
Uh, have you
noticed that Michelle
has been acting a
little strange lately?
You think we ought
to get her a man?
No, we don't have to do that.
No, she can get
any man she wants.
All she has to do is
give them the signal.
- Signal?
- Yeah, didn't you know women...
They give these signals to men
when they want to catch them?
- Yeah?
- Yeah, yeah.
See, they do these things to
make themselves noticeable.
And that brings
up the three A's.
www.tvsubtitles.net